Finding Aid for Marion Celestia Siney papers, 1929-1941
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Marion Celestia Siney papers 1929-1941
Siney, Marion Celestia, 1913-
2 linear feet
861100 Aa 2
Student in history at the University of Michigan, also teaching assistant in the department of history. Class notes, examinations, research papers, reading notes, and lecture notes.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Marion Celestia Siney (donor no. 6819 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Marion C. Siney was born August 11, 1913 in Muskegon, Michigan. She attended Muskegon Junior College in 1929 then transferred to the University of Michigan in 1931 where she received her bachelor's (1933), master's (1934) and doctorate in history (1938). She held a post-doctoral fellowship during 1938-1939 and then became a teaching fellow. In 1941, she received appointment as an in instructor at Western Reserve University.
The Siney collection consists of class notes, examinations, research papers, reading notes, and lecture notes from history and political sciences courses taken at the University of Michigan, 1931 to 1941.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of History.; University of Michigan--Student notebooks.
- University of Michigan course materials
  - 1931/1932
    - History 117. Medieval Civilization. Professor E.W. Dow (Box 1)
    - History 120. The Renaissance. Professor E.W. Dow (Box 1)
    - History 33. English History to 1760. Professor L. Manyon (Box 1)
    - History 34. English History Since 1760. Professor S.M. Scott (Box 1)
    - Political Science 51. English Government. Professor L. Preuss (Box 1)
    - Political Science 52. Continental European Governments. Professor L. Preuss, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1932/1933
    - History 92. Europe Since 1870. Professor H.M. Shermann (Box 1)
    - History 97. The French Revolution and Napoleon. Professor A. Louis Dunham (Box 1)
    - Education 125. Method of Teaching Social Studies "Teaching the French Revolution and Napoleon in a World History Course." Professor Stephenson (Box 1)
    - Political Science 161. International Law. Professor L. Preuss (Box 1)
    - Political Science 162. International Law. Professor L. Preuss (Box 1)
    - Political Science 181. Introduction to Political Science. Professor Reeves (Box 1)
  - 1933 Summer Session
    - History 1025. Greek History. Professor Arthur Boak (Box 1)
    - History 1035. Roman History. Professor Arthur Boak (Box 1)
  - 1933/1934
    - History 82. German History. Professor B.W. Wheeler, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - History 98. Europe 1815-1871. Professor H.M. Ehrmann (Box 1)
    - History 249-250. Seminars in European Diplomatic History. Professor H.M. Ehrmann, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - History 133-134. English Constitutional and Legal History. Professor A.L. Cross, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - Political Science 143-144. American Constitutional Law. Professor J.S. Reeves, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 1934/1935
    - History (Roman History). Professor Arthur Boak (Box 2)
    - Reading Course in Roman History. Professor Arthur Boak (Box 2)
    - History III. The Reformation. Professor A. Hyma (Box 2)
    - History 249-250. Seminars in European Diplomatic History. Professor H.M. Ehrmann (Box 2)
    - History 143-144. American Constitutional History. Professor L. Vander Velde (Box 2)
  - 1936/1937
    - History 108. Europe 18T1-1914. Professor H.M. Ehrmann (Box 2)
    - History 34. British Foreign Policy 1870-1914. Professor S. Morley Scott (Box 2)
  - 1937 Summer Session
    - Political Science. Sixth International Summer Session in International Law. (Box 2)
  - 1937/1938
    - History 149. Italy. Professor H.M. Ehrmann (Box 2)
    - History 250. Seminar in European Diplomatic History. Professor H.M. Ehrmann (Box 2)
  - 1938 Summer Session
    - History 108. Europe 1871-1914. Professor H.M. Ehrmann (Box 2)
  - 1939/1940
    - History 11. Western Civilization. Professors B. Wheeler and D. Long (Box 2)
  - 1940 Summer Session
    - History 147. The War of 1939. Professor H.M. Ehrmann, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 1940/1941
    - History 153/154. English Constitutional and Legal History. Professor S. Morley Scott (Box 2)
  - 1942 Summer Session
    - World War II. H.M. Ehrmann (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous history exams, 1929 (Box 2)